Jia Amanda Cooper

Full stack developer with a background in ESL education over five years and in two foreign countries. My student-focused method of teaching translates into a client-centered approach, where my soft skills of patience, care, and diplomacy are interleaved with my hard skills of software engineering and web development in order to create an end product that matches the vision of my clients.

Full Stack Web Developer Software Engineer

Linked In: www.linkedin.com/in/jia-amanda
GitHub: www.github.com/cooperama

Email: cooperama.8@gmail.com

PROJECTS & DEVELOPER EXPERIENCE

General Assembly, Los Angeles, Remote

Software engineering and full-stack web development immersive program, providing the most relevant and current training on today's tech, tools, and best-practices.

- <u>Co[de]pendent</u> A forum-style app build with a MERN stack and using the FullCalendar JavaScript library to implement a scheduling system. Also using SASS, Moment, and Fontawesome.
- <u>Wayfarer</u> A community where fellow travelers can see and discuss where they've been. Built with Python/Django with PostgreSQL and SASS.
- Flixr A web application that helps the indecisive find and select movies that match their mood and interests at the moment and create playlists for future binge-sessions. Built with MongoDB, Express, and Node.js and implementing The Movie Database's web API.
- Motchi-Gotchi A simple game based on the classic 90s Tamagotchi Pet game.
 Built with vanilla Javascript, HTML, and CSS.

WORK EXPERIENCE

GATE School, Seoul, South Korea

Homeroom Teacher, February 2019 – February 2020 Gifted and Talented Education for kindergarten students.

- Taught basic English starting at phonics, and building up to reading sight words, full sentences, and short stories.
- Introduced thematic topics related to students' everyday lives allowing for interesting and exciting discussion and listening.

4D Content English, Montevideo, Uruguay

ESL Teacher, July 2017 – February 2019

Business English education for adults, in-company and remote.

- Evaluated student levels and skills and selected materials and textbooks based on students' personal and business goals.
- Introduced grammar and vocabulary using relevant, genuine source materials.

Puruni Childcare Center, Seoul, South Korea

ESL Teacher, March 2015 - February 2016

Cared for young children aged 4-5, including three children with special needs, and taught basic English as a second language.

- Created new games and activities through which children could learn new vocabulary and basic phrases
- Completed monthly portfolios detailing the purpose, process, and results of various classroom activities
- Contributed to an online community of Puruni Childcare educators by posting biweekly lesson and activity ideas

SKILLS

JavaScript | HTML | CSS/SASS

Node | Express | React | Python

Django | Bootstrap | Materialize

jQuery | Mongoose | MongoDB SQL

| CRUD | RESTful Routing

EDUCATION

General Assembly

Software Engineering Immersive December 2020

Michigan State University
Bachelor of Science in Nutritional
Sciences